

+49 163 2255913



dogan.mlevent@gmail.com



mldogan.github.io



PhD

Berlin, Germany

EDUCATION

Technische Universität Berlin

Berlin Mathematical School Phase 2 Subject: Mathematics

Supervisor: Prof. Dr. Peter Bürgisser

Master's Degree 10/2017-11/2019

11/2019-present

Technische Universität Berlin Berlin Mathematical School Phase I Subject: Mathematics

Grade: 1.0 (Excellent)

Bachelor's Degree 09/2014-08/2017

Middle East Technical University Subject: Mathematics CGPA: 3.99

EXPERTISE

Programming Languages

- Python, C, C++, Java
- SageMath
- Julia
- Macaulay2

Languages

- Turkish (native)
- English (fluent)
- German (B2)

M. Levent Doğan

M.Sc.

SUMMARY STATEMENT

I am a PhD student at TU Berlin and a Berlin Mathematical School Phase 2 student. My supervisor is Prof. Dr. Peter Bürgisser.

I am interested in computational problems in the areas of algebra, geometry and combinatorics.

My main research is on geometric complexity theory and geometric invariant theory.

PUBLICATIONS

I) Polynomial Time Algorithms in Invariant Theory for Torus Actions

In 36th Computational Complexity Conference (CCC 2021).

with Peter Bürgisser, Visu Makam, Michael Walter and Avi Wigderson.

DOI: 10.4230/LIPIcs.CCC.2021.32

arXiv: 2102.07727

2) The Multivariate Schwartz-Zippel Lemma

In SIAM Journal on Discrete Mathematics. Vol. 36, Iss. 2 (2022).

with Alperen A. Ergür, Jake D. Mundo and Elias Tsigaridas.

DOI: 10.1137/20M1333869

arXiv: 1910.01095

2) On the Complexity of Chow and Hurwitz Forms

In ACM Communications in Computer Algebra. Vol. 57, Iss. 4 (2024).

with Alperen A. Ergür and Elias Tsigaridas.

DOI: 10.1145/3653002.3653003.

arXiv: 2202.11582

PREPRINTS

· 2013

3) Deterministic Approximation Algorithms for Volumes of Spectrahedra

with Jonathan Leake and Mohan Ravichandran.

arXiv: 2211.12541

GRANTS AND AWARDS

• **2019 - present** ERC Grant 787840

European Union's Horizon 2020 research programme

• 2019 - present Berlin Mathematical School

Admission to Phase 2 studies

• 2017-2019 Berlin Mathematical School

Scholarship for Phase I studies

• 2014-2017 Middle East Technical University and TUBITAK

Scholarship for Science Studies

• 2014 National University Admission Exam

55th place among >1.5 million participants 5th National Human Sciences Olympiads

1st degree for Philosophy

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

• 10/2022 - 04/2023 Teaching Assistant

TU Berlin - Algebra I

• 2021 - present Mentor at a Directed Reading Program

I have mentored 3 students at DRP Türkiye

• 2016 Student Assistant

Middle East Technical University

• 2015 Student Assistant

Middle East Technical University

RESEARCH VISITS

• I I / 2023 I visited my co-author Michael Walter

Ruhr University Bochum

• 12/2022 I visited my co-author Alperen A. Ergür

University of Texas at San Antonio

• **06/2022** I visited my co-author Michael Walter

Ruhr University Bochum

• **09/2021** I visited my co-author Elias Tsigaridas

Inria Paris

CONFERENCES AND TALKS

• 07/2023 SIAM Conference on Applied Algebraic Geometry 2023

Eindhoven

I gave a talk in the minisymposium Efficient Symbolic and

Numerical Algorithms for Polynomial Systems

• **06/2023** Foundations of Computational Mathematics (FOCM) 2023

Paris

• **06/2023** 25th Conference of the International Linear Algebra Society

Madrid

I gave a talk in the minisymposium Semidefinite matrices:

geometry and optimization

• I I / 2022 Dies Mathematicus event

I presented my master's thesis at TU Berlin

• 09/2022 Peterfest: Geometry in Complexity and Computations

Konstanz

• **07/2022** Math+ P-NP event

· 08/2021

I gave a "What is..." seminar talk on the PCPTheorem

• **04/2022** Seminar on Geometry, Probability, and Computing

Talk at the colloquium of University of Texas San Antonio. SIAM Conference on Applied Algebraic Geometry 2021

SIAIT Contended on Applied Algebraic Geometry 2021

I gave a talk at the virtual minisymposium Applied Invariant

Theory: Statistics and Algorithms

• **08/2021** Seminar on Nonlinear Algebra

Leipzig

I gave a talk at the colloquium of MPI MiS

• 07/2021 Computational Complexity Conference 2021

I gave a talk at the virtual conference on the accepted paper Polynomial Time Algorithms in Invariant Theory for Torus

Actions

• 02/2020 Milestone Conference of the Thematic Einstein Semester

Berlin

I gave a talk on my preprint The Multivariate Schwartz-

Zippel Lemma